[Music]
hello and welcome to this session where
we talk about bringing AI to core
financials in business Central my name
is Mike porch cardana I'm a product
manager on the business Central
engineering team and I work on AI and
other ways to make our users productive
with business Central and joining me
today are my colleagues my name is Brian
Nelson I'm a program manager within the
business Central team and my name is
George chanic I'm a developer in the
business Central
team and together we're going to give
you a quick demo of this new copilot
capability uh we're going to show you
how to get things set up so that you can
get Hands-On try it out or even demo
this easily to your customers and of
course along the way we'll share some
great tips on how to use this in March
2023 we introduced you to Dynamics 365
co-pilot the world's first AI powered
assistant for both Erp and CRM and in
business Central co-pilot had one skill
marketing text suggestions uh the
ability to draft compelling marketing
text uh and give our customers that
boost of productivity to help them craft
that text and bring their products to
Market
quicker now our vision for copilot has
always been to unlock productivity for
workers across roles across Industries
across lines of business uh so it was
only natural that we' next turn our gaze
towards core Erp processes to see where
AI can help uh we found that some
Financial activities are often
repetitive they're tedious they can be
timeconsuming uh reconciling your
account statements is probably one of
them and here's a good place for us to
leverage large language models and their
ability to uh interpret language
language ambiguity uh understand intent
compare texts U and do simple problem
solving and really help our users get
through this
activity so we're excited to introduce
business Central's second co-pilot
capability bank account reconciliation
assistance with co-pilot uh co-pilot is
built on Microsoft's industry-leading uh
security privacy compliance and
responsible AI which means you can trust
that your data especially the sensitive
financial data that you work with every
day uh is safe it's not leaking outside
of your organization um it is not being
used to train other AI models in fact
our philosophy is that your data is your
data and these are the principles on
which we build bank account
reconciliation
assistance this is now available in
public preview with 2023 release Wave 2
so Brian what exactly is bank account
reconciliation bank reconciliation is a
tedious task sometimes uh it's a
repetitive task and it's also timec
consuming it is the process of making
sure that what your bank says has
happened in your real bank account is
reflected in your EIP system so During
the period you will register customer
receipts you will register vendor
payments and at the end of the period
you'll make sure you'll double check
that it all that you have registered
matches your bank statement and that is
the process of bank reconciliation we've
had this feature for many releases we've
improved it over the past few releases
with this
release we will let coopar assist you in
the process and you can gain some extra
efficiency in doing Bank rck Georgia
will show you some of the examples and
scenarios that copilot can assist you
with uh let me show you the capabilities
of co-pilot blended into the bank
account reconciliation process so with
this release we have introduced a new
action reconcile with co-pilot on the
bank account reconciliations
list when you choose that
action you can see a new dialogue uh new
type of dialogue in business Central um
that is tailor made for interactions
with co-pilot and on this uh dialogue
you can see that a bank account has
already been chosen that is because this
is the only bank account that has a bank
statement import set up on it so we
already choose that one um and the next
thing that the the user should do is to
import their transaction data this can
be either a file or a online bank feed
in case that this bank account is linked
to an online bank
account um in this uh demo I will show
it with a file so we import a file the
file
contains some uh deposits uh from your
bank account and uh the the business
Central reads the statement date uh from
the
file and now that you have a file
imported you can choose
generate uh choosing generate will will
do two things it will first uh try to
match the statement lines from the
imported files uh from the imported file
with the business Central buil-in
algorithm for matching lines and then
for all the lines that are not match by
business Central built-in algorithm it
will call co-pilot and ask it to match
the remaining lines so let's try and
click generate
here and now it is it is trying to match
first with a built-in algorithm uh and
then calling
co-pilot once co-pilot returns a
response we parse the response and try
to um to correlate it with your
statement lines and bank account Ledger
entries and yes in this case you can see
that uh this demo is made so that our
built-in algorithm did not match any of
the lines from the file but co-pilot
actually was able to match all of them
and that is because they are
deposits that are created for multiple
bank account Ledger entries in your
system um here you can see in this in
the bottom section of the page you can
see the co-pilot proposals for matching
these statement lines from the file and
you can see that each one of them was
applied to multiple Ledger
entries uh you can drill down on each
one of
them and you can see that this line was
matched to these Ledger
entries uh this other one to some other
Ledger entries and you can see that the
amounts sum
up it is important to to state that none
of the co-pilot proposals are
saved in the in the in your database
until you explicitly keep the proposals
by choosing this button keep it you can
also choose the button that discards
everything uh it will then just revert
to the list and it will not save
anything um you can delete an individual
proposal from this list if you don't
like it you can choose the delete line
but let's not do it for this
demo um and uh a nice thing that you
have on the page is the visual indicator
of how much of the lines are actually
matched uh in this case you can see that
all the lines are
matched uh that you should review
proposals and you can do it by drilling
down and in the case that all the lines
are matched by our built-in algorithm
and
co-pilot together uh you can also choose
to post this bank account reconciliation
if it is fully applied so if you choose
this checkbox and you keep all these
proposals the bank account
reconciliation is
posted and you can you can see it as a
bank account statement that it's posted
and now let me show you an example of a
of a bank account reconciliation in
which you it is required to do a little
bit more manual work assisted by
co-pilot for this demo I will invoke the
action reconcile with co-pilot and
import another
file that I have prepared it is
practically it is a superet of the of
the file from the previous demo it it
just has a few more lines that are
not uh possible to match with any bank
account Ledger entry in the system so
let's see how that
works so if for this file if I choose
generate and try to match the lines from
the
file yeah in this case we can see that
co-pilot matched 10
lines but there are are three lines that
remain that are not matched either by
our built-in algorithm or
co-pilot and um in this case let's say
we review these uh matches made by
co-pilot and we like them and we say
keep notice that because not all the
lines are matched we cannot choose the
post if fully applied it's because there
are the post would fail because there
are still some lines that are not
applied so let's let's uh choose keep
it and it will ask you if you want to
open the bank account reconciliation
card and yes let's do that here on the
card you can see that the number of
lines are matched but but these three
lines that are look like
expenses they are not matched to any
bank account Ledger entry and in fact
there is no bank account letter entry
that is open for this bank
account typically before this feature
you could you could transfer these lines
to a general journal and and then post
general journal but we have introduced
uh an automation for this process that
uses co-pilot and you can transfer to a
g
account and you can uh multi select
these three lines here
and choose transfer to GL account what
this will do is it will try to find the
best suitable GL account for each of
these lines based on their description
and based on the GL account
name and it will it knows which
reconciliation it is knows which bank
account it is so there is no need to
import any file it just just call scop
Pilot right away and let's see what
co-pilot has
suggested uh it says that uh there are
uh 10 matched lines up front but
co-pilot matched three more of them and
co-pilot is suggesting to for this line
fuel to post a new payment to GL account
passenger car costs you can see that
fuel description is not a substring of
passenger car costs but co-pilot was
able to to to match this uh
semantically um and uh we like this uh
staff wages it suggests to post to
salaries
account let's keep that and uh theater
it suggests to post to outdoor and
transportation
ads I don't like that one that
suggestion so let me drill down and uh I
can actually choose another
g account to transfer this
to and uh let's let's pick this one film
TV radio and so
on just to show that you can
change and it changed it based on your
manual uh
choice you can even use the the
save uh drill down here and uh what this
will do it will it will add this
description as text to account mapping
it will save it in your
database and for future uh future
reconciliations it will map this text
fuel with with g
account um so let's say again because
all the lines are now
matched uh we like these
proposals and uh let's say postive fully
applied again and say keep
it and it will apply these and it
actually posted reconciliation and you
can look at it so after that fantastic
demo let's walk through a couple of
additional details that will help you
plan your
approach first and foremost this feature
is available uh in public preview while
we assess feedback from our community uh
when should you expect to see this well
this will be delivered in a minor update
for Wave 2 now keep in mind that minor
updates span from November until March
2024 uh so if you're on update 23.0 you
will not see this feature you need to
wait for that minor
update uh also like all of our co-pilot
capabilities um bank account
reconciliation assistance is only
available for business Central online
what we often refer to as
SAS now the feature is not restricted by
any country localizations which means
that whichever country localized envir
enironment you are using you will find
the feature there um and also no matter
which language user language you are
using uh the feature will also be
available however we do have a few
limitations in preview that I want to
call out um while in preview co-pilot
performs better in English language uh
with English Bank transactions and in
fact uh suggestions might not perform as
well in other languages uh we also know
that co-pilot does not necessarily
perform as well when you have a mixed
language situation for example when
you're uh Bank transactions have
descriptions in in mixed language now
speaking of transactions Georgia uh one
of the challenges with experiencing bank
account reconciliation is of course
getting your demo data set up having
those right transactions in place um
could you share with us how we've
improved that experience yes so in uh in
business Central evaluation company for
business Central online there is a demo
bank account
reconciliation um for for us version it
is for the checking account
and if you just open
it uh you will see few lines uh and few
bank account Ledger entries and on this
demo bank account reconciliation you can
just choose reconcile with
co-pilot and it will
enter it will call co-pilot straight
away there's no need to import a file
and you can see that
our uh built-in algorithm matched one
out of three lines based on description
and amount and date and co-pilot matched
two out of three lines
uh it matched the deposit line because
it is a one one statement line to
multiple Ledger entries this is
something that the business Central
built-in algorithm is not good at but
co-pilot is and it also matched this
statement line despite the transaction
date being off by 3 days or even more
days co-pilot can handle that so in this
demo bank account reconciliation you can
you can quickly see the capabilities of
co-pilot with these few characteristic
lines that are a bit tough for our bu
built-in matching algorithm that's a lot
easier to get started really but there's
also a few more things you need to know
few more prerequisites before you can
actually try this out so first of all if
you're upgrading from an ear earlier
version of business Central uh such as
version 22 you'll first need to visit
the feature management page uh to enable
this feature now this requires elevated
permissions so you typically an admin
who does this on the environment search
for Bank uh and it should show up then
you just enable it from all users and
the next time you sign in or your
co-workers sign in they will now get
access to this co-pilot capability if
you don't find the feature in this list
named bank account reconciliation that
probably means you're still waiting for
that update to be delivered to your
environment next thing to do is make
sure co-pilot is actually up and running
for that environment so admin should
visit the new co-pilot and AI
capabilities page this gives you an
overview of all of the capabilities
installed specifically to that
environment uh again you'll find bank
account reconciliation here in the
preview section of course uh and it
should be active by default now in many
cases co-pilot will just work without
any additional setup required uh here it
says your environment is connected to
Azure open AI service for your region if
you see this you're good to go however
if your environment localization is um
in a country or region where Azure open
AI service is not available um then the
only way to work with co-pilot is to
connect to Azure open ey service in a
different region and for that um
administrators must first give their
consent that business Central will
contact Azure open AI service in that
different region you do that using the
switch right here and you'll also find
the list of measure Regional services in
our
documentation this single switch
allowing data movement is really the
last thing uh that remains for you to
experience co-pilot in business
Central now while you're trying it out
we'd love to get your feedback uh we
know that AI doesn't always get things
right um in fact we provided a very
simple way for you to signal and rate
that feedback uh rate the quality of
feedback that co-pilot comes up with um
and you can do this every single time
you you reconcile you can do this every
time you suggest jail accounts uh do
send us your likes do send us your
dislikes uh whether you're an end user
whether you're a partner trying this out
or demoing this this feedback really
helps us continue improving business
Central all right so before we close
let's summarize uh what we heard today
um we're bringing co-pilot to core Erp
processes uh with this new capability to
assist in bank account reconciliation
starting out in preview uh you'll find
it in minor up date to 2023 release Wave
2 uh there's no restrictions on country
or region uh in terms of environment
that you can try this on um but some
limitations do apply in terms of
language and if you don't see the action
to reconcile with co-pilot there's
probably some one onetime setup that you
need to go and do as an admin on that
environment uh start by checking out the
feature management page see if you've
gotten the feature there uh and do
remember to provide feedback of course
now if you're a partner watching this
you're probably wondering how how did
they do that well we have some good news
for you because bank reconciliation
assistance has been built using our new
developer tools for co-pilot in business
Central and what that means is that you
can now design and Implement your own
similar uh generative AI capabilities
for your extensions we've got an entire
dedicated session where we go through
this in great detail and if you're
looking for more inspiration more use
cases uh where co-pilot can be put to
work um check out our other session on
on marketing Tech suggestions as well
and last but not least if you're looking
for more in the area of Finance in 2023
release Wave 2 uh check out this one
session on allocations that we also
recommend so there's plenty more
resources for you if you're looking to
get started with business Central uh
follow the buzz on social media or
connect with the product engineering
team um if you've got that great idea uh
where you think we should put AI to work
in the finance area or elsewhere in
business Central do share your idea at a
aka.ms BC ideas and for partners
specifically we definitely recommend you
join the discussion discussion group
called co-pilot and AI uh here's a link
that you can join uh on our Yammer
Network so with that it's been a real
pleasure to share with you how we're
bringing AI to core Erp processes uh
we're really looking forward to hearing
your feedback um while you use this
while you try it out and as you bring
that to your customers as well and we
hope this also inspires you to see a
path toward building your own generative
AI capabilities in your extensions as
well so on behalf of the business
Central engineering team thanks for
watching